singhmamta2789@gmail.com

Mamta Chauhan

Software Developer

7054655966

P-181 Kesav Puram Awas Vikas scheme no-1,kalyanpur 208017, Kanpur Uttar Pradesh,

A highly focused Software Developer with Six years experience in a variety development and engineering positions. Organised, methodical and a keen ey for detail results in solid coding and trustworthy software programmes Understanding client requirements and communicating the progress of projects are core values in achieving long lasting business relationships. Highly resourceful, innovative, and competent PHP developer with extensive experience in Back-End development and testing. Led company-wide integration with third-party APIs and i alos worked in the layout, design and coding of websites specifically in PHP format. Looking for a suitable developer position with an ambitious & exciting company

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Developer

Dataman Computer System Pvt. Ltd

12/2021 - Present

Kanpur Uttar pradesh

Duties:

- Building PHP webportal using PHP based frameworks :CodeIgniter, Cakephp
- Planning and conducting cross-browser usability testing against W3C & Frontend development: React JS,HTML, JSON, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, JQuery, Ajax, Rest API
- Testing and validating work produced as part of the development process.
- Third-party services:Twilio,PayPal, PayU
- Back end development and maintenance of webportal using PHP and MySQL
- Creation and updating of Custom objects, Custom fields, Custom Tabs, Page Layouts, lightning page layou
- Working with a multi-disciplinary team to convert business needs into technical specifications.

PREVIOUS EXPERIENCE

Software Developer

Second World Solutions

06/2017 - 10/2021

Kanpur Uttar Pradesh

Tasks/Achievements

- Worked with designers, Front End and project management staff to capture requirements for the functional elements of website projects. Also responsible for liaising with clients and ensuring that all work carried out complies with standards and guidelines

Executive Developer

Oylex webtechnology Pvt. Ltd

05/2016 - 05/2017

HONOR AWARDS

Silver Medal

CII (Confederation of Indian Industry)

- For Regional Work Skills Competition at Ludhiana

ADDITIONAL AREAS OF EXPERTISE



KEY SKILLS AND KNOWLEDGE

Implementation Management, Application Development ,Customer Interaction,Project management, Ms office proficiency

Operating Systems :Windows/Linux

RECENT PROJECTS

RealEstate

- PHP8, Sql Server Codelgniter 3 http://realbuilderapp.dataman.in/

Vastralaya

PHP8, Sql Server ,CodeIgniter 3 http://103.231.40.199/cms

Paperbrizz (paper Industry)

 PHP8, Sql Server ,CodeIgniter 3 http://103.210.30.117:8080/dms/

Academic college

- PHP8, Mysql, CodeIgniter 3 https://dmschool.phpwork.co.in/iait

School

PHP8, Mysql, CodeIgniter 3 http://103.210.30.117:8080/mdps

Ricemill

- PHP8, Sql Server ,Codelgniter 3 http://103.210.30.117:8080/aahaar

EDUCATION

M.C.A. (Computer Application) 2010 Indira Gandhi National Open University New Delhi

B.C.A. (Computer Application) 2007 Indira Gandhi National Open University New Delhi